At the time that you started working in computer music,
most computer usage was for purposes like accounting and ballistics calculations.
What made you even think of using computers as a creative tool?
I had come to Stanford in 1962 from three years studying in Paris
with Nadia Boulanger, who was a well-known teacher,
and people such as Aaron Copland.
And Quincy Jones and I were there at the same time studying.
So she was an important figure in Paris, musical circles.
But as important to my own education as Nadia Boulanger
was the musical scene in general in Paris.
Pierre Boulez was a young avant-garde enfant terrible,
often referred to in such a way, in Paris
and had a series of concerts, the Domaine Musical,
in which he played.